Guide to the Arthur L. Dahl Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Arthur L. Dahl papers
1932-1953
SC0205
Dahl, Arthur L., 1880-1952
4.5 Linear feet
Class notes, exams, over twenty short stories and other papers relating to his Stanford days.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Arthur L. Dahl, Jr., 1979.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
A member of the El Tigre Club and The Chappie, Dahl received his a.b. in economics in 1934, his m.b.a. in 1938.
Description of the Collection
Class notes, exams, over twenty short stories and other papers relating to his Stanford days.
Access Terms
Dahl, Arthur L., 1880-1952; Manuscripts (for publication).
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - "Mostly notes for college newspaper article", Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Working papers, Spring 1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Working papers, Spring quarter, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Working papers, Autumn quarter, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Working papers, Winter quarter, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Working papers, Winter quarter, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Working materials for paper on the rubber industry, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Working papers, Fall quarter, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Business contracts notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Tax procedure notes, 1938? (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Contemporary novel, Spring quarter, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Regulations Needed for American Investment Trusts, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - English 15, Escape: A Literary Autobiography, 1934 Feb 5 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - An Anthology of Comment on Twentieth Century Music, Edited and with an introduction by Arthur Dahl Jr. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - English 15, Reading Notes, 3/14/1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - English 15, Do Literature and Ether Mix? A Study of the Effect of the Radio Upon Literature, 3/5/1934 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - International Study of Literature, Winter 1934 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - English 13: Biographies, Spring 1932 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Extemporaneous Speaking, Spring 1932 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Aesthetics, Autumn quarter 1933 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Music Fundamentals 2, Spring quarter 1934 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Musical Fundamentals Notebook, Winter quarter 1934 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Voice Training 149, Autumn 1932 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Class final examinations (blue books, essays), 1931-1934 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Class notes/reading notes, 1931-1934 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Law class notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Business law II notebook, Winter 1934 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Business law I notebook, Autumn 1933 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Blue book examinations, 1931-1934 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Blue book examinations, 1931-1934 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Why Listen to Modern Music" essay and drafts, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "The Plight of American Music" essay and draft, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Copies of stories indialect: Negro, 1928 Dec 15 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Death in the Dark" manuscript and draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "The Murder in the Pool" manuscript and draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "The Cabin on Lonely Mountain" manuscript and draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "On Sundry Greetings" essay and draft, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "It Must Have Been Fate" short story, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Gridiron Ballet", Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Cottage Small", Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Hitchhiker", Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Opera Super" short story, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "Rich Man, Poor Boy" short short story, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Stubby" manuscript, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "A Damn Clever Young Fellow" short story, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "The Outlaws" manuscript, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Short Stories" manuscript, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Talk in Behalf of the Christian Science Monitor", Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Schoolwork: odds and ends worth saving, 1928-? (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Chemistry in Relation to Agriculture" essay, Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Rejection slips of Arthur Dahl Jr. (3), Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous college papers, 1931-1934 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous college papers, 1931-1934 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Senior moments, 1934? (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - College odds and ends (massive), 1931-1934 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Stanford sports momentos, Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Poetry, Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - School papers, 1927? (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Alumni's stuff, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "Twenty Years After: 1933-1953" survey (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "Twentieth Reunion: Bawl-Out", 1956 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Eleventh Annual Stanford Business Conference, July 21-25, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - File relating to Amship Corp., 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Community Enterprises, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - San Francisco Junior Chamber of Commerce, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Star Ranch, Inc., 1947-1956 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Story of the Redwoods, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Chaparral work momentos, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - American Trust Company checkbooks, 1931-1934 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - American Trust Company (bank) documents, 1931-1934 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Wilkie buttons, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Work with the McCall company, 1931 Jun, Jul (Box 3, Folder 5)